

RAKESH CHOKSI

Business Head

Career highlights

An Engineering Professional with over 33 years of hard core experience, hands on Merchandising, Category Management, Online Channel category management, Sales Development, Wholesale and Distribution Network servicing, Supply Chain Managment while reaching out to Exclusive Brand Outlets

- EBO's Operations, Multi $\bf Brand\ Outlets$
- MBO's and Large Format Stores **LFS**Business management.

Portico New York Home, Bed, Bath & Linen. Category management for all channels Multi Brand Outlets, Wholesale/Distributor, Large Format Stores all, Institutional Supplies, Star Hotels. Dealt with GHCL, Valiant Glass, Ahmedabad Printers, Trivec, Dishan Etc. for Procurements. Handled Mattel, Disney etc various Kids Characters. We were Importing products like Soyabean. Handled Home production of Bed sheet manufacturing, Quilting (Comforters) and Pillows.

In Welspun since inception developed and managed Kitchen, Dinning, Leaving and Accessories Soft and Hard goods. Launched Curtain Fabric Offering in Organized Retail.Rolled Out Ready Made Curtain in Pan India 250 EBO Stores (Exclusive Brand Outlets) WELHOME. Also handled SPACES BRAND KDLA as a Category Head.

Launched **J.Hampstead** the premium Suiting and Shirting brand of **Siyarams** Silk Mills Ltd. Looking Right from Yarn, Fabric Manufacturing (In-house and Outsourced), Finishing,Range Planning With Sales Responsibility servicing to 200 wholesale/distribution channel partners and 700 Multi Brand Outlet dealers PAN India. Have an Exposure to various material Cotton, Wool, Linen, Polyester, Viscose, Bamboo. Spinning, Weaving, Finishing, Printing and Making technologies.

Contact

Mob: $+91\ 9321114902$

Email: rakeshchoksi@gmail.com

Experience

• Business Head

KIAANA Home Originale, USA, HOME BEE, USA October 2018 to till date and August 2010 to June 2015. KIAANA Home Originale, USA, Luxury Bed Bath & Home Linen Brand. HOME BEE, USA, Mid to premium home linen.

• Consultant

KRA

June 2015 To September 2018 Handled Shandar Curtains, Pearl Thermoplast, Bombay Furniture

• General Manager – Category & Business Development.

Creative Portico India Pvt. Ltd, Mumbai. August 2009 to July 2010.

Worked with Portico New York Luxury home textiles & TOMMY HILFIGER Bed, Bath, & Linen.

• Dy. General Manager-Kitchen, Dining, Living & Accessories

WELSPUN RETAIL LTD, Mumbai, India. August 2005 to July 2009. Spaces by Welspun & Welhome, Retail Store Brand

• Brand Marketing Manager.

Siyarams Silk Mills Ltd, Mumbai August 1991 to July 2005. J.Hampsted the premium suiting & shirting's brand of Siyarams Silk Mills Ltd

• Plant Head

Dupon Silk Industries Pvt. Ltd, Thane, Maharashtra. May 1988 to Dec 1990. Rollout of Yarn doubling & Weaving Plants.

Education

• V.J.T.I, Mumbai University
B. Textile
1988

• V.J.T.I, Mumbai University

Diploma in L.T.M 1985 Rakesh Choksi Curriculum Vitae

Work Experience

KIAANA Home Originale, USA, HOME BEE, USA

Business Head

October 2018 to till date and August 2010 to June 2015.

- Brands Handled: KIAANA Home Originale, USA, Luxury Bed Bath & Home Linen Brand. HOME BEE, USA, Mid to premium home linen.
- Achievements: Launched KIAANA Home Originale, USA, Bed Bath Home Linen successfully, PAN India catering to 200 plus MBO's Dealers/LFS Large Format Stores.Reached out to big A++ top retailers in Bed, Bath, Home Linen and Gift Noveltystores in 1st year of operation itself.
- KIAANA, HOME ORIGINALE USA & Home Bee, PRODUCT CATEGORIES ARE, BED SHEETS, DUVECOVERS, COMFORTERS, DUVETS, COLOUR COMFORTERS, PILLOWS, TOWELS & HOME ACCESSORIES LIKE CANDLES, FRAGNANCES, LAUNDRY BAGS & MANY MORE...

KRA

Consultant

June 2015 To September 2018.

- Category & Product Life Cycle Management, Wholesale, Distribution & Retail to dealers, LFS Stores & Shop-in-shops. Retail Merchandise planning, Building Quality Retail Space for the brand and increasing visibility, E-commerce business, SCM & IT co-ordination, Learning, Trainning & Development of front end team.
- Brands Handled: Shandar Curtains, Pearl Thermoplast, Bombay Furniture
- Achievement: Launched above brands in Hypercity and Other Large Format Stores. Helped brands to prepare complete product plan, development to suit as per profile of stores. End To end rollout and managing Sales.

Creative Portico India Pvt. Ltd, Mumbai.

General Manager – Category & Business Development.

August 2009 to July 2010.

- Brands Handled: Portico New York Home & Tommy Hilfiger Bed, Bath.
- Achievements: Launched new category of readymade curtains, developed kids licensing curtains & other product categories and grown the overall business Like to like 12% during recession period too, while reviving the MBO & LFS product portfolios & operations servicing standard.
- Worked with **Portico New York** Luxury home textiles & **TOMMY HILFIGER** Bed, Bath & Linen. Portico also has the licensee brands in kids, Bed & Bath home category portfolios like Disney, Mattel's, Barbee, Nick, MTV & Cartoon Network part of Creative Group, Mumbai. Portico is India's No. 1 premium bed, bath, home linen brand.

Rakesh Choksi Curriculum Vitae

WELSPUN RETAIL LTD, Mumbai, India.

Dy. General Manager-Kitchen, Dining, Living & Accessories August 2005 to July 2009.

- Brands: Spaces by Welspun & Welhome, Retail Store Brand
- Business Turnover handled: 40 crores & above.
- Reporting to: CEO & Managing Director
- Achievements: Complete Category Management right form inception. Contributed significantly while implementing the business in SAP Retail. rolled-out 250 Exclusive Brand Outlets stores. Contributing 30% of turnover.

Siyarams Silk Mills Ltd, Mumbai, Flagship Company of Siyarams Poddar Group.

Brand Marketing Manager.

August 1991 to July 2005.

- Brand: J.Hampsted the premium suiting & shirting's brand of Siyarams Silk Mills Ltd
- Reporting to: Vice Chairman Shri Ramesh Poddar
- Business Managed: 50 crores & above.
- Achievements: Launched J.Hampsted brand in India in the year 1997 successfully.
- Brand Sales Planning. Product Portfolio Management. Sales Projection & Category Development Production Planning and Operations. Supply Chain Management. Wholesale & Distribution network set-up while reaching to 700 Channel partners. Team Training & Development

Dupon Silk Industries Pvt. Ltd, Thane, Maharashtra.

Plant Head.

May 1988 to Dec 1990.

• Achievements : Rollout of Yarn doubling & Weaving Plants.

Personal Details

• Date of Birth: 25th May 1964.

• Languages : English, Gujarati, Marathi, Hindi.

• Present Renumeration : 20 Lac

• Address : Andheri West, Mumbai - 400 053